## Ben Cheah

+65 9127 3780 benjchb@gmail.com bencheah.com

1 Lorong 30 Geylang Singapore 398242 I'm a product designer who is fluent in both design and code. As the lead UX designer in a product team, I led with best practices in design research, usability testing, prototyping, and accessibility.

## Experience

- UX Designer, GovTech Singapore Jan 2018–Jan 2021
   As a UX lead of My Legacy, I led multiple features, including the design system and a major redesign of the website's information architecture.
   Outside of my project work, I also facilitated design studios for the UX team and managed two direct reports.
- Independent iOS Developer Jun 2016–Jul 2017
   Independently built and launched an iPhone app for travellers to save places to their personal map and easily find what they're looking for on the go.
- UX Designer, RYDE Technologies Nov 2015–Apr 2016
   As the sole UX designer, I brought the team on board design thinking and guided product discussions to centre on user experience. In addition to user research and product design, I also developed tools and visualisations to improve data analytics.
- Web Developer, National University of Singapore Oct 2013–Apr 2015
   I designed and developed an online course platform for the Special
   Science department. Lecturers could use it to create supplementary
   lessons and quizzes to make their lessons more engaging.
- Data Visualisation Artist, Deloitte Analytics Jul 2012–Mar 2013
   I designed and developed interactive data visualisations which were used to demonstrate and sell complex data analytics concepts and cutting edge services to our clients.

## Education

- Nanyang Technological University, Singapore Bachelor of Fine Arts, 2008–2012
- Singapore Polytechnic Diploma in Multimedia Technology, 2003–2006

## Skills

UX & UI Design, Design Research, Frontend Web Development, React Web Frameworks, iOS Development